Psychologists have long been in disagreement as to whether competition is a learned or a genetic component of human behavior.
对于竞争是人类行为中后天习得的成分还是遗传的成分，心理学家长期以来一直意见不一。
Whatever it is, you cannot but recognize the effect competition is exerting in academics and many other areas of contemporary life.
无论属于哪一种，你都不得不承认，竞争正在学业以及当代生活的其他许多方面产生影响。
Psychologically speaking, competition has been seen as an inevitable consequence of human drives.
从心理学角度来说，竞争一直被视为人类内驱力的必然结果。
According to Sigmund Freud, humans are born screaming for attention and full of organic drives for fulfillment in various areas.
按照西格蒙德·弗洛伊德的说法，人生来就哭喊着要人关注，并且充满了想在各方面得到满足的生理内驱力。
Initially, we compete for the attention of our parents.
起初，我们争夺的是父母的关注。
Thereafter, we are at the mercy of a battle between our base impulses for self-fulfillment and social and cultural norms which prohibit pure indulgence.
此后，我们便受制于一场斗争：一方是我们追求自我满足的低级冲动，另一方是禁止纯粹放纵的社会和文化规范。
Current work in anthropology has suggested, however, that this view of the role of competition in human behavior may be incorrect.
然而，当前的人类学研究表明，对于竞争在人类行为中所起的作用，这种看法可能是错误的。
Thomas Hobbes, one of the great philosophers of the seventeenth century, is perhaps best remembered for his characterization of the “natural world”, that is, the world before the imposition of the will of humanity, as being “nasty, brutish, and short.”
托马斯·霍布斯是17世纪的伟大哲学家之一，他最为人铭记的，或许是把“自然世界”（即人类强加自身意志之前的世界）描述为“肮脏、野蛮而短暂”。
This image of the pre-rational world is still widely held, reinforced by Charles Darwin’s highly influential work, The Origin of Species, which established the doctrine of natural selection.
这种前理性世界的图景至今仍广为接受，查尔斯·达尔文极具影响力的著作《物种起源》确立了自然选择学说，又强化了这一图景。
This doctrine, which takes for granted that those species best able to adapt to and master the natural environment in which they live will survive, has suggested that the struggle for survival is an inherent human trait which determines a person’s success.
这一学说理所当然地认为，那些最能适应并主宰自身所处自然环境的物种将会存活下来；它还暗示，生存斗争是人类固有的一种特性，决定着一个人能否成功。
Darwin’s theory has even been summarized as “survival of the fittest”—a phrase Darwin himself did not coin—further highlighting competition’s role in success.
人们甚至把达尔文的理论概括为“适者生存”（这个说法并非达尔文本人首创），这进一步凸显了竞争对成功的作用。
As has often been pointed out, however, there is nothing in the concept of natural selection that suggests that competition is the most successful strategy for “survival of the fittest.”
然而，正如人们常常指出的那样，自然选择这一概念中并没有任何内容表明，竞争是实现“适者生存”的最成功策略。
Darwin asserted in The Origin of Species that the struggles he was describing should be viewed as metaphors and could easily include dependence and cooperation.
达尔文在《物种起源》中断言，他所描述的斗争应当被视为隐喻，完全可以涵盖依存与合作。
Many studies have been conducted to test the importance placed on competition—as opposed to other values, such as cooperation—by various cultures, and generally conclude that Americans uniquely praise competition as natural, inevitable, and desirable.
为了检验不同文化对竞争（相对于合作等其他价值观而言）的重视程度，人们已开展了许多研究，这些研究普遍得出结论：唯独美国人把竞争称颂为自然的、必然的、可取的。
In 1937, the world-renowned anthropologist Margaret Mead published Cooperation and Competition among Primitive Peoples, based on her studies of several societies that did not prize competition, and, in fact, seemed at times to place a negative value on it.
1937年，世界著名人类学家玛格丽特·米德出版了《原始民族的合作与竞争》一书，该书基于她对几个社会的研究，这些社会并不看重竞争，事实上，有时似乎还对竞争持否定态度。
One such society was the Zuni Indians of New Mexico, and they, Mead found, valued cooperation far more than competition.
新墨西哥州祖尼印第安人的社会就是其中之一；米德发现，他们重视合作远远超过重视竞争。
After studying these cultures, Mead came to the final conclusion that competitiveness is a culturally created aspect of human behavior, and that its prevalence in a particular society is relative to how that society values it.
研究了这些文化之后，米德最终得出结论：竞争性是人类行为中由文化造就的一个方面，它在某一特定社会中的盛行程度，取决于该社会对它的重视程度。